Guide to the Cedric Belfrage Papers TAM.143
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: Addendum, 1923-2003
  - Belfrage Family; Letters to Cedric and Mary, 1980-1989 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Belfrage Family; Letters to Cedric and Mary, 1990-1996 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Belfrage, Mary; Biography, notes for, undated (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Belfrage, mary; correspondence with Sally Belfrage, 1990-1994 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - Belfrage, Mary; family tree, undated (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - Belfrage, Mary; friendship with Shart [French painter], 1960s (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - Belfrage, Mary; Letters to Cedric, 1959-1961 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Belfrage, Mary; travel; letters from Mary Belfrage, 1958-1959 (Box 27, Folder 43)
  - Belfrage, Mary; Writings re Cedric, 1990-1991 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Bernick, Mary; Jentelson, Lee; correspondence, poetry, ect., undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Birthdays, [list of dates for friends and relatives, undated; 2001 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Bradford, Virginia; letters to Cedric Belfrage, 1920s-1930s (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Cuba; Cedric Belfrage, manuscript (article length), undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Cuba; letters to/from Cedric and Mary Belfrage, 1966-1969 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Cuernavaca guests; letters, 1991-1996 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Hollywood; filmed interview of Cedric by Kevin Brouslow, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Hollywood; Research interview of Cedric by Sue McLonachy, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Book, notes for (Cedric Belfrage), undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Memory of Fire (Geleano book); letter by Tom Englehardt, undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Palmer, Jennifer; Belfrage PhD; FBI files, 1960s (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Palmer, Jennifer; correspondence with Mary Belfrage, 1995 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Publishers and Agents, 1980-1994 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - South America; travel notes re Cuba, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Txalaparta editorial, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Wallace, Bert H.; "Sands of Sorrow: A Semi-Political Autobiography", 1989 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - "McCarthy and the Army: A Fight on the Wrong Front" / Norman Dorsen (Columbia University Forum), Fall, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - "The German Who Should Have Been Dead" / Cedric Belfrage (Harper's Magazine; June, 1948, pp. 511-517), Jun 1948 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - The Minority of One: Five Issues, each with an article by Cedric Belfrage, Oct 1967-Sep 1968 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - "Reflections: On Political Exile" / Cedric Belfrage (The Progressive; August 1977, pp. 20-21), Aug 1977 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - "Post-Inquisition: The Exile Returns" / Cedric Belfrage (Rights; Jun-Jul 1973, pp. 3-8; the journal of the National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee) (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Voight the Nineteenth Century & After Limited and Constable & Co., Ltd. v. News Chronicle, Ltd., The Daily News, Ltd., and Cedric Belfrage -- In the High Court of Justice: King's Bench Division (London). Transcript, 221 pp., Jul 10, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - VHS Tapes Featuring Cedric and Mary Belfrage, 1983-2003 (Box 31)
  - Unprocessed Videos (Box Shared Tamiment 024)
  - Oswaldo Guayasamin art, undated (Flat-file-folder 6)
- Series VI: Photographs and Bust, 1923-1999
  Approximately two hundred photographs document Cedric Belfrage's extensive travels to China, Nepal, Cuba, Egypt, the USSR and other countries. There are many portraits of Belfrage from the 1920s through the 1980s, as welll as photographs of family and friends. Individuals represented in these photographs include Paul Robeson, Scotty Mackenzie, Claude Williams, Owen Whitfield (organizer for the Southern Tenant Farmers' Union) and Colonel Raymond Robins.
  - Belfrage, Cedric: Portraits, 1923-1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Cropperville, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Cuba, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - General, 1930s (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - General, 1940s (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - General, 1950s (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - General `, 1960s (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - General, 1970s-1990s (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - General, undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Mackenzie, Scotty, 1934-1958 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - People's Institute For Applied Religion (Claude C. Williams), undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Robeson, Paul, 1957-1958 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Travel (China, Napeal, USSR), 1950s (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Whitfield, Owen, 1955-1963; undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Head of Cedric, Undated; cuid853; 1 item (Item TAM.143.cuid853)
    Scope and Contents
    Artist: Elizabeth Catlett
    busts (figures)